今天是投票日
This election day,
我们边界的命运掌握在你的手中
the fate of our borders is in your hands.
约翰·莫尔诺打算邀请
John Moreno wants to invite
非法移民进入我们的国家
illegal immigrants into our country.
他要把我们的工作机会让给他们
He wants to give them our jobs.
让他们享受我们的医保福利
He wants to give them our healthcare.
约翰·莫尔诺想圆了他们的美国梦
John Moreno wants to give them the American dream,
但他想让你为这一切买单
and he wants you to pay for it.
约翰·莫尔诺
John Moreno
他究竟站在哪一边
Whose side is he really on?
这个问题很重要
It's a valid question.
他喜欢放宽政策
He favors easing restrictions.
我也是
So do I.
得了  哈尔
Come on, Hal.
这和你对发放工作签证的立场没关系
Your position on work visas is irrelevant.
他所讲的是获取绿卡的问题
He's talking about a path to citizenship.
我告诉你  这条广告会为你赢得选票
I'm telling you, this AD wins you the election.
却侮辱了一位我的主赞助商
By insulting one of my core constituencies.
想想吧  在04年的时候
Come on, in '04
我曾拥有45%拉丁裔的选票
I had 45% of the latino vote.
而今年你遇上了与一个叫"莫尔诺"的家伙
And this year you're running against a guy named Moreno.
这里可不是你的地盘
This isn't one of your races
不是南卡罗来纳或是俄克拉荷马州  乔
in South Carolina or Oklahoma, Joe.
这里可是新泽西  人们投我票
This is New Jersey-- people vote for me
-是因为我是温和派的  -那敢情好啊
- because I'm a moderate. - Well, that's great.
你会成为国内最温和的前参议员
You can be the most moderate ex-senator in the country.
哈尔  距投票日还剩七天了
Hal, the election is seven days away,
就连我们自己的内部统计都显示
and even our own internals show
你落后了6个点
you down six points.
我们总是不被看好
We've always been the underdog.
但我们也总会找到办法获胜  我坚信
And we've always found a way to win. I know.
那是因为你总是让我做那些必须要做的
Because you have always let me do what's needed to be done.
我要在明天播这条广告
Now, I can have this on the air tomorrow.
不  不行
No, no.
别这样  哈尔  让我播吧
Come on, Hal, let me do this!
不  绝对不行
No, absolutely not.
这会彻底地刺激左翼分子
This could totally galvanize the left.
你没事吧  乔
You all right, Joe?
我好像出皮疹了
Yeah, I think I got some kind of a rash.
什么鬼东西  那可不是皮疹
What the hell? That's not a rash.
或许我应该去看医生
Maybe I should call a doctor.
你最好叫辆救护车
You better call an ambulance.
看看吧...
Look at it like this...
所有的骨折方式中
Of all the ways to rupture it,
没有比让真正的阿喀琉斯从小桶上
nothing honors the real Achilles more
滚下来摔骨折更荣耀的了
than blowing the dismount on a keg stand.
什么味道
What's that smell?
洋葱吗  还是胡椒
Is it onions? Peppers?
我知道了  是男士聚会
Oh, I know... It's a Sausage Fest.
男士聚会有很多种
Sausage Fest implies multiples.
如果你是说球赛
Now, if you're talking about yardage,
我再同意不过了
I'd have to agree.
我在说你的部门成员
I'm talking about your department.
你还没有找到人代替13的位置
You still haven't replaced thirteen.
很快就有了
It's coming along.
你找人时间够多了
You've had plenty of time to find someone.
我也找了很多的人  只是一个都没留下
I've found plenty of someones. Just haven't kept them.
别玩了  该结束了
It's time to end the cycle.
来见见你们的新队友
Meet your new team member.
她叫玛莎·M·马斯特斯
Her name is Martha.M.Masters.
这位医生还没毕业
This doctor is not a doctor.
她是个三年级的医科生
She's a third-year med student.
她15岁就高中毕业了
She graduated high school when she was 15.
她在进医学院之前
She filled out the time before med school getting Phds
攻读了应用数学和艺术史博士学位来打发时间
in both applied math and art history.
如果我下一个病人是一幅埃舍尔[错觉图形艺术家]
She'll be incredibly useful
的画作  她一定能帮上大忙
if my next patient is an Escher drawing.
这些真是扯淡
Those things are seriously screwed up.
这不是建议
This isn't a suggestion.
不要以为我和你做过小爱爱
Just because my sausage has been filling your bun
就意味着你可以决定
doesn't mean you get to decide
白天我吃什么味的薯条
what flavor chips I nosh on during the day.
不是  我可以决定是因为我是你老板
Nope, I get to do that because I'm your boss.
患者名叫乔·杜根  42岁  政治顾问
Patient is Joe Dugan, 42, political consultant.
因皮肤隆起性紫癜入院
Presents with palpable purpura,
ALT[谷丙转氨酶]和AST[谷草转氨酶]骤升
and ALT and AST are through the roof.
也就是皮疹和肝脏损伤  太吸引人了
Otherwise known as rash and liver damage. Fascinating.
病人是安德森参议员送过来的Senator
Senator Anderson sent this case to us,
亲自打招呼叫我们看一下
and personally requested we take a look.
这对我来说是充足的理由了
That's reason enough for me.
黑小子为反对党助选吗
Black guy campaigning for the opposition?
奥巴马知道这件事吗
Does Obama know about this?
我试过给他打兄弟热线
I tried calling him on the brother hotline.
他没接
He didn't pick up.
玛莎·M·马斯特斯
Martha.M.Masters.
我是豪斯医生
I'm Dr. House.
这是其他的组员
This is the rest of the team.
这是"无聊"  "蠢妞"
Boring, Bimbo,
还有"一口大"
and Bite-size.
玛莎很喜欢一元二次方程
Martha enjoys quadratic equations,
意大利壁画还有其他刺激的事
Italian frescoes, and her turn-ons include
比如学着当大夫
learning to be a doctor.
坐吧
Take a seat.
她是个医学院学生吗
She's a med student?
卡迪认为她很有天赋
Cuddy thinks she's some kind of genius.
来点有创意的吧
Say something brilliant.
我...我不...
Oh, I...I don't...
-阿塞拜疆的首都是哪儿  -巴库
- Capital of Azerbaijan? - Baku.
-贝多芬哪年死的  -1827年
- Year Beethoven died? - 1827.
-尤拉方程的第20位小数是  -6
- 20th decimal of Euler's number? - Six.
这是我最爱的常数
It's my favorite constant.
她像个带咪咪的百度
She's like the internet with breasts.
不  等等  应该是长了咪咪的百度
Oh, no, wait-- the internet has breasts.
我们的病人有肝损伤
Our patient's liver damage
可以解释皮疹和血液中
explains the rash and cryoglobulins
出现的冷球蛋白
we found in his blood,
但是我们搞不清肝脏损伤的原因
But we can't explain the liver damage.
没有证据表明患者有药物或酒精滥用
Shows no other signs of drug or alcohol abuse.
我们现在要做的就是分出谁是"蠢妞"
Now all we've gotta do is figure out which one is Bimbo
谁是"一口大"
and which one is Bite-size.
还有就是哪辆怪物卡车赢了
Also, which monster truck won
2004年度的雷霆全国赛
the 2004 Thunder Nationals?
丙型肝炎解释得通
Hep C makes sense.
检测结果阴性  症状和甲肝乙肝相同
Test came back negative. Same for Hep A and B.
我们要找的答案就是弗吉尼亚巨人
The answer we were looking for is Virginia Giant.
你随便参加哪一组讨论都行
Feel free to chime in on either conversation.
我不想夺走我们的小奇迹说话的机会
Hate to steal the spotlight from small wonder over here,
但也有可能是中毒
but what about toxic exposure?
可能是四氯乙烯
Tetrachloroethylene.
甚至是薄荷油或黄樟油
Could even be pennyroyal or sassafras oil.
去他家看看  找出化学品
Go to his house, get me some chemicals.
如果你想在这个团队呆下去
You wanna stay on this team,
就要发表意见
have an opinion.
酷
Oh, cool!
都铎复兴式的建筑
Tudor revival architecture.
入口上方是不对称的尖顶
Steeply pitched, asymmetrical roof over the entrance.
但是外墙并没有用半木质机构
But it doesn't have the half timbering over the facade.
一点医学有关的都没说
Doesn't say anything about medicine,
说起建筑倒是滔滔不绝  很好
can't shut up about architecture. Great.
我明白  我不知道为什么
I know. I don't know what happened.
一靠近豪斯...
Being around House...
他就是个传说  他太有威严了
He's such a legend, he's so intimidating.
我不喜欢跟泛泛之辈混在一起
I'm not like that around ordinary people.
我不是说你们是泛泛之辈
Uh, not that you guys are ordinary.
只是他太睿智了
It's just that he's so brilliant
你们在他手下干  你们就没那么耀眼了
and you work under him, so you're not as imposing.
我该闭嘴了
Um... I'm gonna be quiet.
很明智
Good idea.
杜根没给你们钥匙吗
Dugan didn't give you a key?
如果病人知道我们要来
If patients know we're coming,
他们就会有意无意地把有关疾病的
they can hide something relevant to their illness
东西藏起来
intentionally or unintentionally.
让他们知道会影响调查
Their knowledge changes things.
你是吸血鬼吗
Are you a vampire?
没关系  我们邀请你进来
It's okay. We're inviting you in.
但是我们的病人不会
But our patient didn't.
我不能这样做  对不起
I can't do this, I'm sorry.
很好  她真是帮大忙了
Well, she's gonna be a big help.
闯进陌生人的房子
Yeah, what a rube being uncomfortable
是件多么鲁莽的事啊
breaking into a stranger's house.
这就是我们工作一部分
Part of our job description,
还不算是道德最模糊的部分
not the most morally ambiguous part.
给她个机会吧
Give her a chance.
她年轻又有激情
She's fresh, enthusiastic,
没有不良习惯  不用纠正
has no bad habits we need to reteach.
她是个没有临床经验的医学生
She's a med student with no practical experience.
意味着每项操作  每次抽血
That means every procedure, every blood draw,
她都需要我们其中一个看着
she needs one of us there to supervise.
你这样看她是不是
Is this attitude about her
因为她还没有获得医学博士学位
not having an M.D. After her name?
因为我想知道她能做点什么
Because I wonder if it has more to do
证明她是个小超人
with her being a brainiac.
根本不是那么回事
That's not it at all.
谁是最聪明的人
I'm not thrilled someone else
我一点也不感冒
might be the smartest person on the team now.
我能体会你的感受
I can only imagine how you feel.
你不比我聪明
You're not smarter than me.
是吗  你找到这个了吗
Oh, yeah? You find this?
一壶未经高温灭菌的苹果汁
A jug of unpasteurized cider.
可能沾染了大肠杆菌
It could be tainted with E coli,
大肠杆菌会引起肝脏损害
and that's what's causing the liver to shut down.
大肠杆菌只在动物中传播
E coli is found in animals.
除非他喝了猪肉苹果汁...
So unless he's drinking pork cider...
猪肉苹果汁
Pork cider!
我需要专利局的电话
I need the number of the patent office.
大肠杆菌可以通过间接方式感染
There are indirect ways of attracting E coli.
马斯特斯拒绝和我们入室搜寻
Masters refused to go on the search with us.
有意思  谁挑起的这个问题
Interesting. Which raises the question,
你和她之间怎么了
what is your problem with her?
他被她的高智商给吓着了
He is intimidated by her intelligence.
这有什么好让陶博烦恼的
Why would that bother Taub?
他已经和比他更聪明的人
He's been working with people smarter
一起工作很久了
than him for a long time.
我觉得是一个神气的小女孩
I think perky new girl
让他觉得自己老了
makes him feel old.
她基本上和13岁的小女孩没差
She's basically the same age as thirteen.
是的  但她是个医学院学生
Yeah, but she's a student.
让你回想起你自己的学生生涯
Makes you contemplate your med school days.
那时你还没谢顶  肌肉发达
Back when you had hair, muscle tone,
也不需要定期做前列腺检查
and no need for a regular prostate exam.
有道理
Makes sense.
就像大肠杆菌
Just like E coli.
果园将卖不出去的苹果
Orchards make cider out of apples
榨成汁
they can't sell otherwise,
比如那些掉到地上  摔坏了的
like if they've fallen onto the ground.
或是掉进牛粪里的
Like, into some cow feces.
也就是说  我们受人尊敬的病人
Which would mean our esteemed patient
的确是满嘴大粪啊
is literally full of B.S.
酷  带上那个天真少女
Cool. Go get the ingenue,
给病人用噻肟单酰胺菌素并做血浆置换
start the patient on Aztreonam and plasmapheresis.
他说要给病人用噻肟...
He said to start the patient on Aztre...
细胞分选仪将血浆
The cell sorter separates the plasma
和血细胞分离开
from the remaining cellular components,
这样可以排除...
thereby removing...
毒素  抗体  冷凝球蛋白
The toxins, antibodies, cryoglobulins.
我觉得我们应该告诉病人
I think we should tell our patient
我们闯入过他家
about breaking into his house.
为什么
Why would we do that?
因为不告诉他的原因是
Because the reason not to tell him
怕他隐藏些什么东西
was that he might hide something.
而现在这个理论已经没用了
And now that rationale is moot.
现在的理论
The rationale now
是没有好处  只有坏处
is no upside, big downside.
我们怎么能让病人相信我们
How can we ask our patients to trust us
如果我们对他们不诚实?
if we're not honest with them?
我们怎么能在告诉他不能相信我们之后
How can we ask the patient to trust us
重建他对我们的信任
after we tell him he can't trust us?
好吧  去告诉他
Fine. Tell him.
让你的良心好受点
Clear your conscience,
因为那很重要
because that's what's important.
如果你让我把那条广告播出去的话
Well, if you would let me run that AD,
人们会转移目标去讨论移民问题
everybody would be talking about immigration instead.
没错  这就是我们要谈的
All right, look, here's what we're gonna say.
没错  他去过伊拉克
Yeah, he was in Iraq,
我们都为他的奉献感激不已
and we're all grateful for his sacrifice.
而你选择投身公共事业为国家贡献力量
You chose to honor your country through public service
而且投过46次票  建议扩大五角大楼的
and have voted 46 times to expand the pentagon's budget
工程预算  而莫尔诺则持相反意见
for programs which, oh, by the way, Moreno wants to cut.
好的  我起草个文件发给你
All right. I'll draft it up, send it over.
在你出院前
You should probably slow down
你应该放慢工作
until you're out of the hospital.
这周很忙
It's a busy week.
你不好奇我们是怎么做出这个诊断结果的吗
Aren't you curious how we came up with this diagnosis?
你们是医生  你们的职责不是如此吗
You're doctors. Isn't that your job?
但我们怎么知道你喝过苹果汁呢
But how we knew you were drinking apple cider?
你们从我家里找到的
Well, you had to have found that at my house,
所以我猜你们闯入过我家了
so I guess you guys broke in there.
你没有因此不安吗
That doesn't bother you?
医学就像政治
Medicine's like politics.
最终要的是结果
At the end of the day, all that matters is results.
不对
That's not true.
还应该有尊重
Respect matters.
诚实
Honesty
和廉正
and integrity matter.
你想过从政吗
Have you ever thought about running for public office?
因为我太喜欢有你
Because I would love to have someone like you
这样的对手了
as an opponent.
小心别动了输液管
Watch the replacement fluid line.
好的  对不起
Oh, right, sorry.
你难道没好奇过为什么
You ever wonder why American voter
在发达国家里  美国选民
turnout rates are among the lowest
的投票率最低吗
in the developed world?
杜根先生
Mr. Dugan?
怎么了  能听到我说话吗
What's wrong? Can you hear me?
他麻痹了
He's paralyzed.
叫福曼和奇斯来
Call Foreman and Chase, get them down here.
杜根先生
Mr. Dugan!
我们认为是短暂缺血性休克
We thinks it's a transient ischemic attack.
可能在我们找到凝块前  凝块就消了
The clot must have broken up before we could find it.
他是临时性麻痹
He was temporarily paralyzed,
但他会恢复行动和讲话能力的
but he's regaining mobility and speech.
那么  是什么引起皮疹
So, what causes rash,
肝功能衰竭  凝块
liver failure, clots,
还有想逃避开同事
and the uncontrollable urge
不可遏制的欲望
to rat out your coworkers?
不  等等...
Oh, no, wait...
最后一点是说你  不是说病人
That last one was you, not the patient.
我没想临阵脱逃
I wasn't trying to rat.
我只想忠于我的职业道德
I was clearly trying to honor my ethical obligation.
门静脉血栓
Portal vein thrombosis
可能是威尔逊氏病引起的
could be caused by Wilson's disease.
终于开口了
You popped your cherry,
从诊断上讲
diagnostically speaking.
不幸的是  第一次总是很糟糕
Unfortunately, the first time always sucks.
说法一点不靠谱
Pitch doesn't make any sense.
杜根的角膜很正常
Dugan's cornea was normal.
你还真聪明
You're obviously brilliant.
那么你为什么隐藏你的想法
So why would you hide your mind?
我是突然想出来的
I was brainstorming.
我不是说对病人的白痴看法
I'm not talking about your stupid ideas about the patient.
我是说对道德的白痴看法
I mean your stupid ideas about morality.
我白痴的看法是大多数医生遵循的
My stupid ideas are what most doctors consider
职业道德
the rules for professional conduct.
那么神经内分泌肿瘤呢
What about a neuroendocrine tumor?
思考能力还是下降了
Not without diminished mental capacity,
判断失误
loss of judgment.
弥散性血管内凝结  还说得过去
Disseminated intravascular coagulation, however, fits.
规矩是给白痴们定的
Rules are just helpful guidelines for stupid people
给那些没有自主思考能力的人定的
who can't make up their own mind.
很显然  你不该是那类人
You obviously don't fit into that category,
那为什么要把自己划进去
so why put yourself there?
马斯特斯说的那个
Masters is right
神经内分泌肿瘤的论断没错
about a neuroendocrine tumor.
因为杜根有判断力缺失
Because yes, Dugan has had a loss of judgment.
他为安德森做了这个
He made this totally inflammatory
非常有煽动性的反移民商业广告
anti-immigration campaign commercial for Anderson.
这广告刚刚在网上发布了
It just got linked online.
你是说杜根的政治动作
You're arguing Dugan's politics
是他心智缺失的信号
are a sign that he's mentally compromised?
不  是他的战术
No, his tactics.
他是最有可能泄露广告的
He's most likely the one who leaked it
所有评论员都在说
and all the commentators are saying
安德森要食言了
Anderson will catch the major backwords.
说实话  这还真是个好主意
And honesty's a great idea
除非你们的病人问
until your patient asks
她会不会因腹部膨胀而发胖了
if her distended abdomen makes her looks fat.
豪斯  我不想打断你们的伦理争论
House, I hate to interrupt your ethics debate,
但现在我们桌面上摆着两种不同意见
but we have two solid ideas on the table.
给他做颈部到腹部断层扫描
Ct from his neck to his abdomen
看看有没神经内分泌肿瘤
for neuroendocrine tumors.
做二聚体和纤维蛋白扩散实验
Run a d-dimer and fibrinogen for D.I.C.
马斯特斯
Masters.
如果对病人撒谎可以救命的话
If lying to a patient saved their life,
-你会撒谎吗  -不
- would you do it? - No.
这就是一句谎话
That's a lie.
如果你奶奶送给你一个很蹩脚的茶壶套
If your grandma gave you a really crappy tea cozy
做圣诞礼物  你会跟她说你喜欢吗
for Christmas, would you tell her you liked it?
是的  但那不一样
Yes, but that's different.
所以  你在无所谓的时候可以说谎
So, you lie when it doesn't matter
但有所谓时就不会
but you won't when it does.
你怎么这么不靠谱
How'd you get so screwed up?
如果我炒了马斯特斯  你会多有生气
How mad would you be if I fired Masters?
非常  除非你有理由
Very. Unless you had cause.
真正的理由
Real cause.
是人都会考虑的理由
Cause that a human being would consider cause.
那没事了
Never mind, then.
她需要监护人
She's got principals.
她就像是爱因斯坦和玛丽·波宾丝的私生子
She's like the love child of Einstein and Mary Poppins.
但没遗传爱因斯坦的发型
Didn't even get Einstein's hair.
你的团队里还是需要有个
It's worth having someone on the team
不觉得世界满是灰色阴影的成员的
who doesn't see the world entirely as shades of gray.
-就是灰色的  -对你来说
- It is gray! - To you.
她有新鲜的观点
She has a fresh perspective.
除非那威胁到你了
Unless that threatens you.
没有威胁...
It does not...
你以为我是在防御
You thought I'd get defensive,
让她不要骄傲
keep her out of pride.
女孩可以有希望
A girl can hope.
豪斯  这件事我想了很久
House, I gave this a lot of thought.
她值得一试
She deserves a chance.
真正的一试
A real chance.
豪斯要炒了我
House is gonna fire me.
不  他不会的
No, he isn't.
因为你不让他炒我吗
Because you told him not to?
豪斯有很强的逆反心理
Butting heads with house is par for the course.
豪斯有强烈的信念
House has strong beliefs,
而且他尊重有强烈信念的人
and he respects other people with strong beliefs.
我的信念倒不是问题
It's not my beliefs that are the problem.
是我的个性
It's my personality.
我不擅长和他人交往
I'm not good at working with other people.
你在那还没超过一天
You've been in there for less than a day.
我不是来寻求鼓励的
I wasn't looking for encouragement.
是事实
It's a fact.
在成长过程中  我的一生  真的
Growing up, my whole life, really,
我一直在独处
I-I spent a lot of time by myself.
高中里没有一个人想和
And no one in high school wants to hang out
小自己三岁的小孩儿玩
with a kid that's three years younger than them.
而阿诺索夫微分同胚研究
And studying Anosov diffeomorphisms,
说明不论一个无属性区域
determining whether an unattributed landscape
是封闭还是开放还是...
is a blakelock or a ryder or...
我现在就正在让你厌烦
I'm actually boring you right now.
但是你选择的是医学
And yet you chose medicine
就需要团队合作
which is a team activity.
真勇敢
It's pretty gutsy,
让自己远离你的舒适地带
stepping so far outside your comfort zone.
我不是想证明什么
I'm not trying to prove anything.
我只是想当医生
I just wanted to be a doctor.
很愚蠢吧
It was stupid.
没人能万事通
Nobody can do everything.
我曾梦想我能够胜任
I was vain to think I could be the exception.
豪斯不会在乎你善不善长团队合作
House doesn't care if you're a team player,
或者你有多么有道德
or how ethical you are,
或者你的智商有多高
or how high your I.Q. Is.
只要能解决病例
It's all about the cases.
你帮助他解决好这个病案
You help him crack this one,
你们两人就会相处好的
you two are gonna get along just fine.
我们该给马斯特斯一点建议
We gotta give masters some pointers,
帮助她对付豪斯
help her figure out how to deal with house.
为什么要这个
Why would I do that?
看热闹什么的  最有意思了
The entertainment factor is off the charts.
就像是看鹬蚌相争
It's like watching a bunny hop into a buzz saw.
反复来去
Repeatedly.
如果我们不帮她  她又得离开了
And if we don't help her, she's out of here.
不  会有东西阻止豪斯炒掉她的
No, something else is stopping House from firing her.
我猜是他想和卡迪嘿咻的渴望
I'm guessing it's his desire to keep having sex with cuddy.
你们准备好承认自己错了吗
You guys ready to admit you were wrong yet?
抱歉你说什么
Excuse me?
你们要找的肿瘤  不会找到的
This tumor you're looking for-- you're not gonna find it.
我的判断力很健全
My judgment is completely sound.
那你泄露那条广告的时候
So when you leaked that AD,
你是想破坏参议员的竞选吗
you were trying to torpedo the senator's campaign?
好吧  第一  我跟你说过
All right, one, I told you before,
我没泄露那广告
I didn't leak that spot.
第二
And two...
不管是谁放出的广告
whoever did leak that ad
脑子都没进水
had nothing wrong with their mind either.
它会解救安德森的
It's gonna save Anderson.
那条商业广告...
That commercial...
每个人都看明白了
Everyone sees through it.
你只是想利用人们的恐惧
You're just trying to play to people's fears.
你说是恐惧
You say fears.
我说是理性的自保本能
I say rational, protective instincts.
从你的口音看
And judging by your accent,
要求你在移民问题上不偏不倚
immigration probably isn't an issue
不太现实
you can be real impartial about.
我等了五年才拿到绿卡
I waited five years to get my green card.
如果有人反对在移民手续上走捷径
If there's anyone who would resent
第一个就该是我
someone trying to skip the queue, it'd be me.
只因为莫尔诺支持特赦令...
Just because Moreno favors amnesty...
他不支持
He doesn't.
你们看过他跟墨西哥国旗一起的那张照片吧
You know that picture of him with the Mexican flags
看起来像是在支持移民特赦令集会吗
that seems to be from a pro-amnesty rally?
是他在国际特赦组织发表讲演
That's from an Amnesty International speech
反对墨西哥瓦哈卡州关押牧师的时候拍的
protesting the imprisonment of priests in Oaxaca.
没错  你们刚刚证实了那则广告
Yes, you did just prove that that AD
比你们想象得更龌龊
is even more disgusting than you thought.
你们还证明了那则广告的有效性
You also proved that AD is effective.
你们还认为我判断失灵吗
You still think my judgment is off?
现在不了
Not anymore.
没有肿瘤的迹象
There's no sign of a tumor.
只剩下播散性血管内凝血
That leaves D.I.C.
我去看看陶博血检做得怎么样了
I'll go check how Taub is doing with the blood work.
我猜人一上了年纪
I guess when you get on in years,
连做几项最简单的血检也慢起来了
it takes a little longer to run a few simple blood tests.
考虑到我身材比你更健壮的事实
This whole "Taub's an old man" thing kinda rings hollow,
你"陶博是个老家伙"的论调听起来有点儿假
considering I'm in better shape than you are.
染色剂递我
Pass the dye.
你身材比我圆倒是真的
You're in rounder shape than me.
今晚下班之后
Tonight after work,
体育馆篮球场见
meet at the basketball courts in the gym.
你知道自己身高刚够两尺半吧
You do realize you're two and a half feet tall, right?
而且还是白人加犹太人
And white. And Jewish.
被我赢了一定相当丢脸
It'd be very embarrassing.
我明白你为什么要拒绝
I get why you wanna say no.
今晚下班后见
Tonight after work.
该死
Crap.
你有没有听莫尔诺最新的政治演说
Did you hear Moreno's latest stump speech?
他要净化华府
He's gonna clean up Washington.
太对了
Yeah, right.
搞得好像有哪个新泽西出来的政治家
Like any politician from New Jersey
真正净化过...
has ever cleaned up...
还有谁知道那则广告是你泄露出去的
Who else knows that you leaked that AD?
仅有的两份拷贝在你我手里  哈尔
You and I had the only two copies, Hal.
我不介意你泄密
I don't care that you did it.
我只是想确定它起到了作用
I just want to make sure it worked.
今天上午的调查显示我的支持率只差两个百分点
This morning's tracking has me within two points.
我早说过
Told you.
我们一定会赢
We're gonna pull this thing off.
你的播散性血管内凝血检验结果完全正常
Your blood test for D.I.C. came back completely normal.
这是好消息  对吧
That's good news, right?
这意味着我们的两种推测都落空了
That means the two things we thought it could be, it's not.
我们查过你家  没找到任何毒素
We checked your home for toxins and didn't find any.
但不排除
But it's possible
你在竞选途中接触毒素的可能
you might've been exposed on the campaign.
你有没有走访过工业或者农业设施
Have you visited any industrial or agricultural facilities?
兰伯顿有个番茄农场
There was a tomato farm in Lumberton.
他们带你进菜田了吗
They take you into the fields?
没人想跟我合影  我压根儿就没下车
No one wants a photo op with me. I never leave the bus.
车窗当时开着吗  某些杀虫剂
Were the windows open? Certain pesticides...
福曼
Foreman.
什么  怎么了
What? What is it?
我们现在要担心的不止是你的肝脏了
It's not just your liver we have to worry about.
看样子你的肾脏也出了问题
Looks like your kidneys are having problems, too.
这家伙穷尽一生
So this guy spends his entire life
四处奔波防止别人心灵受创
campaigning against bleeding hearts.
到头来自己的心脏不行了
And it turns out he has one.
尿血是肾脏问题
Bloody urine actually is a renal problem,
与心脏无关
not a cardiac one.
我说了不准确的话
Yeah, if I say something inaccurate,
你就该当笑话听
assume it's for comic effect.
然后大笑  因为它好笑
Then laugh, because it's funny.
可能是血栓性血小板减少性紫癜
TTP makes sense.
血小板多少
What're his platelets?
20万   不是血栓性血小板减少性紫癜
200,000. It's not TTP.
会不会是过敏性紫癜
What about henoch-schoenlein purpura ?
过敏性紫癜不会导致血栓
H.S.P. Doesn't cause clots.
过敏性紫癜通常不会导致血栓  但也有可能
H.S.P. doesn't usually cause clots, but it can.
而且血管炎可以解释肾脏病变
And the vasculitis would explain the kidney problem.
她连笑话都诊断不出
She can't diagnose a joke,
但她对病人的诊断有进步
but she's making progress on the patient.
我们给他化疗  或者用类固醇
We treat with chemotherapy or steroids.
我们给他化疗
We treat with chemotherapy.
我说了化疗
I said chemo.
然后你又说了"或者"
Then you said, "or."
又一次  乖乖兔遭遇无情打击
Once again, the bunny meets the blade.
通向病人死亡之路就是由各种"或者"铺就的
The road to dead patients is paved with "or"s.
化疗是更有效的治疗
Chemo is the more effective treatment
因为它能更快地验证我们的诊断
which means it'll confirm our diagnosis more quickly.
我同意  但还有一种办法
I agree, but there is another option.
办法有很多
There are lots of other options.
放血  水晶  祈祷...
There's bloodletting, crystals, prayer...
我指的是另一种医学公认的方法
Another medically accepted option.
不那么有效  也不那么吓人
Which is both less effective and less scary.
所以病人很可能会选
So the patient might just choose it.
除非我们不告诉他
Unless, of course, we don't mention it to him.
我们不能隐瞒信息
We can't withhold information.
如果我们把两种疗法的风险
If we explain both the benefits
和好处解释清楚
and the risks of each treatment
我确信杜根会选择化疗的
I'm sure Dugan will choose chemo.
只要你确信就好
Well, as long as you're sure.
化疗是更好的选择
The better option is chemotherapy.
见效快而且更可能治愈你
It's faster and more likely to completely cure you.
我选类固醇
I'll take the steroids.
我的天哪
Oh, my goodness!
要是某人早预料到
If only someone could've predicted
你会做这种愚蠢的选择该多好
that you'd make that incredibly stupid decision.
化疗造成的恶心和乏力
The nausea and fatigue from chemo
只会持续几周
will only last a few weeks.
我们的民意调查下滑了
Our poll numbers have stalled.
距离竞选开始只剩5天
That's five days till the election.
医生  你能不能给他讲讲道理
Doctor, can you talk some sense into him?
要是能  我会的
Would that I could,
但是道德支配我尊重他的决定
but ethics dictate that it's his decision.
所以我能做的只是回到办公室
So all I can do now is return to my office
心里知道  即便我的病人危及自身
knowing, even as my patient endangers himself,
我的正直诚实依然清白无暇
my integrity remains unblemished.
求你  花时间考虑一下
Please. Take some time to think about this.
我不需要时间  我要开始用类固醇
I don't need any time. I want to start on the steroids.
1球1分  11分制
Game to 11 by ones.
等等
Uh, hold on.
比投篮吗
Wanna shoot for outs?
你投吧
You can have it.
1比0
One, nothing.
你不防我吗
You gonna guard me?
你又不能连中
Can't hit two in a row.
2比0
Two, nothing.
你到底防不防我
You gonna guard me now?
你有本事就一直投吧
You can have that shot all day.
3比0
Three, nothing.
1比3
One, three.
10比7
Ten, seven.
不是吧
Seriously?
就这样被你赢了
You're gonna beat me with that?
好吧  我错了
Well-- I was wrong.
你没那么老
You're not so old.
谢谢
Thank you.
现在我们只要搞清楚
Now all we have to do is figure out
为什么马斯特斯让你感到不安
why Masters is making you feel insecure.
我刚才在药房
I was just down by Dugan's room.
他们正要给他用错的药
They were ready to give him the wrong medicine.
我想纠正他们  可我不是医生
I tried to change the order, but I'm not a doctor.
很好  错的药才是对的药
Good. The wrong medicine is the right medicine.
但他要的是类固醇  不是化疗
But he wanted steroids, not chemo.
他想活下去
He wants to live.
我要去告诉他真相
I'm gonna tell him what's going on.
不  你不能
No, you're not.
你在理论上怎样讲我不管
I don't mind your morality in theory.
你在实际操作中拿我病人的生命冒险
But in practice, you're risking my patient's life.
所以你被解雇了
So you're fired.
你以为解雇我我就不去告诉他了吗
You think that's gonna stop me from telling him?
你敢去  我保证医学院开除你
If you do, I'll get you thrown out of medical school.
我没做任何应当被开除的事情
I haven't done anything that would merit that.
我知道  但与你不同  我愿意撒谎
I know. But unlike you, I'm willing to lie.
解雇她是个错误
Firing her was a mistake.
我们需要团队里有像她这样的人
We need someone like her on the team,
来约束我们
keeping us all in check.
我做了不应当的事
You're incapable of noticing
你们会看不出来吗
when I do something inappropriate?
我们就像煮了一阵子的青蛙
We're like the frogs who've been in the pot for a while.
已经习惯那热量了
We're used to the heat.
长袜子皮皮出现之前  一切都好好的
Things have been just fine without Pippi Longdivision.
你的对手已经退出竞选
Your opponent's out of the race.
停止诽谤活动吧
You can drop the smear campaign.
杜根出现肺水肿
Dugan developed pulmonary edema.
不是过敏性紫癜
It's not H.S.P.
马斯特斯是对的
Masters was right.
他不想要化疗  他也不需要化疗
He didn't want the chemo. He didn't need the chemo.
马斯特斯是错的
Masters was wrong.
他没患过敏性紫癜
He doesn't have H.S.P.
而且马斯特斯已经走人了
And Masters is gone.
可能是感染
Could be an infection.
我们给他用了氨曲喃治疗大肠杆菌
We had him on aztreonam for the E coli.
他没见好
He didn't respond.
血吸虫病用氨曲喃自然不会见好
Schistosomiasis wouldn't respond to aztreonam.
真是高明想法
That's a great idea,
如果他是在非洲跑竞选的话
if he was running a political campaign in Africa.
他好多年没出过国了
The guy hasn't been out of the country in years.
有了大鱼缸谁还需要出国呀
Who needs to travel when you've got a giant fish tank
满缸的热带鱼  热带蜗牛
loaded with tropical fish, tropical snails
身上满是热带血吸虫之类的热带细菌
carrying tropical bacteria like schistosomiasis.
再去闯他家  抓两只法国蜗牛回来
Well, break into his home, get me some escargot.
除非你们想去讨病人的许可
Unless you wanna ask the patient's permission
当离职礼物送她
as a tribute to the departed.
过来一下
Need a minute.
你答应给她一次机会的
You said you were gonna give her a chance.
我给了
I did!
她利用我给的机会危害病人生命
She used that opportunity to endanger our patient's life.
我坚持让他得到他选择的治疗
By insisting he receive the treatment that he asked for.
我说的就是这个
That's what I just said!
你的团队存在就是为了挑战你
Your team is there to challenge you.
我解雇她不是因为她是个挑战
I didn't fire her because she's a challenge--
我解雇她是因为她是个顽固的障碍
I fired her because she's an immutable obstacle!
你要逼我雇佣她吗
You gonna make me hire her?
你觉得会有什么结果
How do you think that'll work out?
他说的对  我还是
He's right, I'll just--
你不准辞了这份工作
You will not quit this job.
这算什么意思啊
What is going on?
我想让她走  她也不想干
I want her gone, she wants to be gone.
你较的什么劲儿
Why do you care?
你该不会觉得
You don't actually think
她是毕业生版的你吧
that she's a younger version of you?
实话跟你说  你没她聪明
Because let me tell you, you're not that smart
也没她这么道德
or moral.
倒是可能跟她一样不善社交
Socially awkward, maybe.
她很有潜力
She's a potential star,
我想要她为我的医院效力
and I want her in my hospital.
没问题
No problem.
让她换个科室待着去
Just find her a different department.
我想我知道答案了
I think I've figured it out.
为什么陶博不喜欢马斯特斯
Why taub didn't like Masters.
你怎么也加入八卦队伍了
Now you're getting involved in this, too?
我的前娱乐新闻人物被解雇了
My previous source of entertainment just got fired.
没错  她走了  到此结束
Exactly. She's gone. It's over.
她品德高尚为人正直
She's totally moral and uptight,
这让陶博羞于自己出轨之事
which made Taub feel badly about his cheating.
赶紧干活好吧
Can we get a move on?
在你见识到
You didn't like her
她品德高尚之前就不喜欢她了
even before you knew about her morals.
你第一眼看到她就不对盘
It's from the minute he saw her.
那么
So...
肯定是因为她的长相了
It's something about how she looked.
行了
All right.
没有蜗牛  我们走吧
No snails. Let's get out of here.
谁啊
Hello?
-说话  -我是福曼
- Yeah. - It's Foreman.
你们有什么发现
What'd you find?
没什么有建设性的  但
Nothing helpful, but--
一定有原因
There's gotta be something.
杜根的病情持续恶化
Dugan's going completely downhill.
现在他胸腔开始积液了
Now fluid's collecting in his chest.
你们死哪里去了
Where the hell are you guys?
蹲拘留所了
In jail.
你会来保我们出去吗
You gonna come bail us out?
我  有点忙
Uh... Kinda busy.
感谢你们能在夜深时与会
Thank you all for coming down here at this late hour.
我会简明扼要
I assure you I will be brief.
本周初在网络上泄露的一段
There has been a lot of discussion
攻击他人的广告引起了广泛讨论
about an attack ad that leaked online earlier this week.
我曾多次强调
As I said many times
在过去几天
over the past few days--
你躲在这儿啊
There you are.
我正在想是不是我那"比你更圣洁器官"
I was starting to think that my holier-than-thou-dar
最近罢工了
was malfunctioning.
我们病人的肝脏
Our patient's liver,
双肾和肺部齐齐衰竭
kidneys, and lungs are failing.
我需要你帮助我找到病因
I need you to help me figure out why.
我记得  你有三位真正的医生手下
As I recall, you have three actual doctors
今天没被你解雇
you haven't fired today.
他们在拘留所里
They're in jail.
什么  怎么会
What? Why?
搞三人行
Prostitution.
所以你被重新雇佣了
So you're rehired.
一切始于肝脏  问题是肝脏哪里
It all started in the liver, but where in the liver?
如果是胆管  那就是原发性胆汁性肝硬化
If in the ducts, then primary biliary cirrhosis--
停  我不要听你的思考过程
Yeah, I don't need to hear your ideas.
直接回传[回答问题]
Just return the volley.
原发硬化性胆管炎
Primary sclerosing cholangitis.
错  他维他命A水平正常
Nope. His vitamin A level is normal.
胆囊问题会影响肝脏
Gall bladder problems can affect the liver.
胆囊炎
Cholecystitis?
嘘  他在说我们的病人
Shh! He's talking about our patient.
你刚才让我嘘声
Did you just shush me?
别说话
Shh!
我一直把他当朋友
And thought he was a friend.
直到
That is, until...
他泄露了这则令人受伤令人憎恶的广告
He leaked this hurtful, hateful ad.
我觉得他在说谎  杜根说
I think he's lying. Dugan said--
这术语叫做演说
The technical term is speaking.
杜根辜负了我对他的信任
Dugan violated my trust.
因此  除了将他从我的竞选团队中除名
And therefore, I have no other recourse
我没有其它补救办法
than to fire him from my campaign.
谢谢各位  回答问题到此结束
Thank you, and there will be no further questions.
多谢你的帮忙
Thanks for your help.
顺便  你又被解雇了
Oh-- and you're fired again.
他害了你
He screwed you.
手段真他妈高明啊
That was a hell of a move.
利用广告做铺垫
Use the ad to shore up the base,
干掉极端分子抓牢中心
fire the extremist to hold the center.
不  我说他真的害惨你
No, I mean he actually screwed you.
周末游游邦伯里
Taking weekend trips down to Bunbury.
他手上有块红疹
He's got a red blotch on his hand.
那是掌红斑
That's palmar erythema.
再加上他尼克松似的焦虑不安
That, and the fact that he's got
以致长年脸泛红光
a permanent sheen of nixonian flop sweat.
表明他患丙肝
He's got hepatitis C
这能解释你所有的症状
which explains all your symptoms.
那太好了
That's great,
可惜我跟议员没有性接触
but the senator and I have not had sex.
那就是你们同用一根针筒注射
Well, then the two of you shot up together.
你知道多少高功能海洛因吸食者呀
How many high-functioning heroin users do you know?
实际上  还不少
Actually, quite a few.
听着  我知道你有丙肝
Look, I know you've got Hep C.
所以要么你们是共枕同眠
So either you shared a bed together,
或者是共用针头
you shared a needle,
要么就是用了同一根吸管
or you shared a straw.
我在说可卡因
I'm talking about coke,
不是可乐
not coke.
吸食可卡因也会得丙肝吗
You can get Hep C from doing cocaine?
我肯定不会承认的
Look, I will deny it.
随你便
Don't care.
我入院时做过测试
They tested me for Hep C when I came in here.
我没有丙肝
I don't have it.
显然你的肝脏也会几招
Apparently your liver picked up
你的竞选战术
a few of your campaign tactics.
通过制造冷球蛋白
It's hiding all your secrets
它掩盖了你的小秘密
by producing cryoglobulins
所以丙肝测试结果呈阴性
So the Hep C tests come back negative.
本来我可以寻找相关毒素
Now, I could look for all the associated toxins,
但血浆除去法已经把它们都排空了
but the plasmapheresis got rid of those.
简单来说  你生病了
So basically, you've got a disease,
但没法证明
but there's no way to prove it.
挺有意思的对吧
It's pretty cool, huh?
你在打什么
What is that?
这是干扰素
This is interferon.
它可以让你迟些变僵尸
It delays the onset of Rigor mortis.
你律师说他什么时候来
When did your lawyer say he was coming to get us?
他说
He said,
原话重现
and I'm quoting here,
很快
"Soon."
我知道了
I know.
你看马斯特斯第一眼
The reason you hated Masters
就讨厌她的原因
from the moment you saw her.
有完没完
Come on.
你之前就见过她
That was not the first time you saw her.
真聪明
That is brilliant.
真的不是这样
It's really not.
那家伙真要在这上厕所吗
Is that guy seriously using the toilet?
老天  他坐下来了
Oh, my god, he's sitting down.
别想岔开话题
Don't try to change the subject.
你跟她睡过吗
Did you sleep with her?
难怪他被关在拘留所
No wonder he's in jail.
他这么做竟然不感到羞耻
Anyone who would do that has no shame.
也有可能他曾试图勾引她
Or maybe he tried to sleep with her,
被她狠狠拒绝了
and she shot him down.
我不认识她
I don't know her.
他在嗯嗯吗
Is he grunting?
我好像听到他嗯嗯了
I think I hear grunting.
你该知道我们不会善罢甘休吧
You realize we're not gonna drop this.
我没跟她睡过
I didn't sleep with her.
我给她面试进霍普金斯医学院的
I interviewed her for Hopkins med school.
就因为她选了另一所学校
So you're holding a grudge,
你对她心存怨恨
because she chose a different school?
我们对话了一个小时
We talked for an hour.
她竟然不记得我
She didn't remember me.
她记得什么数学常数第20位数字
She remembers the 20th digit of some math constant,
却不记得
but she doesn't remember
跟她一对一面谈的面试官
a guy she had a one-on-one meeting with.
我还不记得你是哪根葱呢
Well, I barely remember you.
迷题解开了
Mystery solved.
现在大家可以回到常轨了
Now we can all go back to our lives.
好消息
Great news.
我决定再次雇佣你
I've decided to rehire you.
换个人耍耍去
Find another sounding board.
杜根患丙肝
Dugan's got Hep C.
我不会搭理你的
I'm not doing this.
干扰素不起作用
He's not responding to interferon.
想必你觉得我完全没有自尊
You must think I have absolutely no self-esteem.
又要道德又要自尊
Ethics and self-esteem?
你还真叫人蛋疼
You really are a pain in the ass.
除了干扰素还有什么能治疗丙肝
What treats Hep C besides interferon?
现在你又想听我的主意了
Now you want me to talk?
是啊
Yeah.
得了  别假装你不想告诉我
Come on, stop pretending you're not gonna do this.
不管你多讨厌我  你更讨厌失败
As much as you hate me, you hate failing more.
我没有失败
I didn't fail.
是你一遍遍炒我
You fired me. Repeatedly.
但现在我重新雇佣你  你还要离开
But if you walk away now, after I just rehired you,
那叫辞职
that's quitting.
一项德国调查研究显示
A german research study
15%的丙肝患者
showed that 15% of patients with Hep C
在感染上甲肝后治愈
were cured after contracting Hep A.
当然其他研究显示
Of course, other studies have shown
85%的双重感染病患
that up to 85% of doubly-infected patients
死得更快
die very quickly.
所以理论上说  如果我们找到甲肝模拟物
So, in theory, if we can find something that mimics Hep A--
是有那么个甲肝模拟物
There's one thing that mimics Hep A...
甲肝呗
Hep A.
不错
Good work.
你被解雇了
You're fired.
不
No!
甲肝能治好他
Hep A could cure him.
更可能杀死他
Better chance it'll kill him.
让实验室给我个甲肝培养物
Tell the lab to release a Hep A culture to me.
看谁对谁错
We'll see who's right.
这项治疗未获批准
It's not an approved treatment
还会对我们产生不利影响
and exposes us to liability.
我不可能让你这么做
There's no way I can let you do this.
你这是极端畏缩的立场
That's an extremely cowardly position.
听听天才之言
Listen to the genius.
是你坚持要他征求我意见的
You're the one that insisted he run this by me.
因为这是非传统治疗的常规机制
It's proper protocol for an unconventional treatment.
可我们不该牺牲病人的安危
But we shouldn't compromise patient care
只为避免诉讼
just to avoid lawsuits.
现在我们无法证明他真有丙肝
What about the fact that we don't
这你又怎么说呢
have any proof he actually has Hep C?
她这反对无懈可击
That is a perfectly valid objection.
别听她的
Don't listen to her.
她又不是我的手下
She doesn't even work for me.
如果你真认为这是唯一能治愈他的办法
If you really think that this is the only way to cure him,
我愿意冒法律风险
I will risk the lawsuit.
但我需要知道他确实患有丙肝
But I need to know that he actually has the disease.
给我证据
Get me proof.
-我已经给你  -证据
- I've given you-- - Proof!
你给我他患有丙肝的证据
Get me proof he has Hep C,
我就让你给他注射甲肝病毒
and then you can give him Hep A.
我无法证明
I can't.
你会想出办法来的
You'll figure something out.
你们俩智商加起来都超过300了
The two of you have a combined IQ north of 300.
五个白痴加起来也是300
That's also true of five morons.
去干活吧
Go. Work.
我们现在怎么办
So what do we do now?
考虑到我正要
Well, considering the fact
做些不道德的事
that I'm about to do something unethical--
懂了  我被解雇了
Oh, right, yeah-- I'm fired.
想你们了
Missed you.
我们需要一份丙肝假阳性测试
We need a false positive Hep C test.
我们要这个干什么
And why would we want to do that?
你们蹲拘留所的时候世界变了
The world changes when you're on the inside.
出来之后你们得跟上
You just gotta roll with it once you get out.
你认为他的丙肝
You think he contracted Hep C
是从议员那染上的  对吧
from the senator, right?
那就测安德森
Test Anderson.
如果他是阳性  就表明杜根也患上了
If it's positive, that's evidence Dugan has it, too.
只是表明  不是证明
Evidence, not proof.
我们又不是呈给陪审团看
Are we presenting this to a jury of our peers?
说服卡迪应该够了
That should be enough for Cuddy.
应该够  但实际不够
Should be, but it won't be.
丙肝测试准确率是99.9%
The test for Hep C is 99.9% accurate.
这意味着一千个测试中
That means one in every thousand tests
就有一个假阳性
is a false positive.
我们多测几次  也许能碰上
We do enough, maybe we get lucky.
我浑身监狱味儿
I smell like jail.
假冒的假阳性
False false positive.
没有更好的办法了吗
That's the best we can do?
那好  行动吧
Okay, go do it.
我遇到个难题
I have a problem.
一个医学问题
A medical problem
可能演变成
which could become...
我骗过卡迪上万次了
I have lied to Cuddy 10,000 times.
你觉得再多骗一次她会怎么想
How do you think she'd feel about 10,001?
我觉得你心里已经有数了
I think you probably already know the answer.
可我想不通呀
But it doesn't make any sense.
你不理解为什么男友一说谎
You don't understand why a woman might be upset
女人就不高兴
because her boyfriend lied to her?
我不会以男友身份对她说谎
I wouldn't be lying as her boyfriend.
而是作为员工
I'd be lying as her employee.
男女关系不是这么处的
That's not how relationships work.
我的病人会死
My patient is gonna die.
说谎能保证他活下来吗
Does the lie guarantee he'll live?
不能
No.
你有两个选择
You got two choices:
诚实  但要面对医疗后果
to be honest and face the medical consequences,
说谎  但要面对个人感情
or lie and face the personal consequences.
既然你是我的医生
Now that you're my doctor, you, uh...
就不可以对任何人说吧
You can't tell anybody, right?
谁会到处宣传现任参议员
Who'd leak a story about a sitting senator
注射可卡因染上了丙肝呢
who got Hep C from doing cocaine?
你没有填写任何表格
You didn't fill out any paperwork.
我会帮你做匿名测试
I'm gonna run this test under an assumed name.
相信我
Trust me--
没人会知道你来过这儿
no one will ever know you were here.
血液测试证实是丙肝
Blood test confirming Hep C.
他的病情加重
He got sicker,
病毒负荷量上升
his viral load came up,
最终在测试中显现出来
finally showed up on the test.
谢谢你
Thank you.
曾几何时
There was a time
你对我的要求视而不见
when you would have completely ignored my request.
你能这么做说明很尊重我  我很高兴
That means a lot that you respect me enough to do this.
我一直在努力  宝贝儿
I've come a long way, baby.
现在就差雇佣一个新成员了
Now, if you would only hire a new team member.
我会搞定的
I'm on it.
来给我干活怎么样
How'd you like to come work for me?
我好像身处莫比乌斯带
It's like I'm on a mobius strip.
我们早就谈过了
We've had this conversation.
你想要这份工作
You want this job.
向我证明自己的能力
Prove yourself to me,
不会再耍你玩了
no more games.
至少现在这场游戏结束了
At least, the current game ends.
还会有其它的
Others may start.
虽然有漏洞  但是我向你保证
You have my deeply-flawed word.
我该做些什么
What do I have to do?
让杜根同意注射甲肝病毒
Get Dugan to let us give him Hep A.
要想找个最好的办法
And while you're figuring out the best way
劝诱病人进行死亡率
to coax a patient into a treatment
高达85%的治疗方案
that has an 85% mortality rate,
我建议你  别告诉他
here's some advice: don't.
我不会骗他的
I'm not gonna lie to him.
你是有数学学位人的
You have a Math Degree.
看看你能不能应用在这上面
So let's see if you can follow along here.
你对他说谎  他肯定会同意
You lie to him, he definitely consents,
也许就能活下来
he might live.
你像上次那样对他讲出实话
You tell him the truth like last time,
他可能就不会同意
he might not consent,
那他一定会死
He definitely dies.
跟我说说谎有什么不对
Remind me what's so wrong about lying?
我们要给你注射甲肝病毒
We're going to inject you with Hepatitis A.
听起来不像是药
That doesn't sound like medicine.
我知道这有违常理
I know it seems counter-intuitive,
但在一些人体内
but in some people,
这种病毒能够增强免疫力
the virus can enhance immune function
清除丙肝病毒
and clear out the Hepatitis C.
一些人  到底是多少人
Some. How many we talking about?
可观的数目
A fair amount.
跟我说下百分比
Give me a percentage.
这种方法的成功率有多高
What are the odds of this thing working?
有85%的可能会致死
There is an 85% chance that this will kill you.
这么说
So, you wanna
你要给我的治疗比喝砒霜的
give me something that works
生还率高个15%
15% better than arsenic?
理论上讲  生还率要高无数倍
Well, technically, it works infinitely better
因为喝砒霜活命的机会...为零
because arsenic has a 0% ch--chance.
这是你唯一的机会
This is your only shot.
我和豪斯医生都这么认为
Both Dr. House and I believe that.
为了给你批这个治疗方案
He faked a blood test in order
他伪造了血液测试
to get you approved for this treatment.
他还试图贿赂我
And then he tried to bribe me
向你隐瞒风险
into lying to you about the risks.
如果这些事情被查出来
If either of those incidents came to light,
他将会停诊
he would be suspended
很可能被吊销执照
and probably lose his license.
肯定还会有其他人跟着受苦
Oh, I'm sure some other people would suffer.
他拿自己的职业生涯作赌注换你这次机会
He's risking his career to give you this chance.
如果还有其他选择  他是不会这样做的
He wouldn't do that if there was any other choice.
我做到了  而且没说谎
I did it. And I didn't have to lie.
你自我感觉很好是吗
And you feel good about that?
-是的  -这么说我雇了个白痴
- Yes. - So I'm hiring an idiot.
你可以假装想让我说谎
You can pretend you wanted me to lie,
但其实不然
but you didn't.
你希望手下的人挑战你
You want the people on your team to challenge you
不然的话  你就只是在欺负人
otherwise you'd just be a bully
而不是个好医生
instead of a great doctor.
你雇我  因为我坚持自己的原则不妥协
You hired me because I don't compromise my principals.
或者我想最先看到  有一天你清醒过来
Or I want a front row seat when you wake up
认识到你的原则有多没用
and realize how useless your principals are.
我不要你单纯欺骗病人
I don't want you to just lie to a patient.
我是要你自愿欺骗病人
I want you to want to lie to a patient.
不会有这一天的
It's not gonna happen.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
我听说杜根的治疗已显成效了
I heard Dugan is already responding to treatment.
是的  他的丙氨酸氨基转换酶水平逐渐正常
Yeah, his ALT level is already beginning to normalize.
我希望跟你说声抱歉  我先前的态度
I wanted to apologize for the way--
等下  你面试过我吧
Uh, wait-- you interviewed me, right?
霍普金斯医学院
For Hopkins?
哦  天啊  还真的是
Oh, my god, you're right.
你的记忆力真好
Wow, that memory of yours.
第一天我就想和你说的
I wanted to say something the first day.
但我总觉得有些尴尬
I felt really awkward about the whole thing.
别这么想
Don't worry about it.
这身是奶奶的茶壶套吗
Is this grandma's tea cozy?
什么
What?
没什么  楼上见
Nothing. I'll see you upstairs.
早知道雇佣她
If I knew hiring her meant
得签署一堆医学院文件
dealing with medical school paperwork,
我会重新考虑的
I might've reconsidered.
你就没其他事可做
You really got nothing better to do
一定要盯着我签字吗
than watch me sign this?
我怎能错过你终于承认
And miss the ultimate admission
我对马斯特斯的看法一直是对的
that I was right about Masters all along?
她说你畏缩的时候我就打定主意要她了
She had me when she called you a coward.
出去玩玩
You heading out?
我得加班
I have to work late.
不是光得意就行的  还得处理一大推文件
Gloating requires a lot of paperwork.
感谢新泽西州人民
Thank you, New Jersey
再次选举我成为州议员
for reelecting me to the United States senate.
这是一次积极的竞选
We ran a positive campaign,
一次直面国家内忧外患的竞选
a campaign about the dire issues facing this great nation.
许多人不遗余力
There are many people who gave their all
支持这次竞选
for this campaign.
但有一个人
But there is one person
付出最多
that stands out among them.
她就是我美丽的妻子洛蕾塔
My beautiful wife, Loretta.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
你知道参议员的病例保存在哪吗
Do you know where the senator's records are?
豪斯治疗的是安德森的竞选经理人
House was treating Anderson's campaign manager,
不是参议员本人
not the senator himself.
为什么你会以为参议员是他的患者
Why did you think he was the patient?
豪斯在门诊会见了他
House saw him in the clinic.
看来不是医疗方面的
I guess it wasn't medical.
什么时候
When?
周五  三点左右
Friday. Around 3.
豪斯小组周五给乔·杜根做了丙肝测试
House's team ran a Hep C test on Joe Dugan on Friday.
你能查下具体时间吗
Can you look up the time?
奇斯  陶博和福曼整夜都在做测试
Chase, Taub, and Foreman were running tests all night.
结果都是阴性
All negative.
呈阳性的测试是在
Positive test at...
下午3点17分
3:17 pm.
豪斯亲自做的测试
House ran it himself.
没什么问题吧
Is everything okay?
有问题
I don't think so.